We are going to be discussing about DNS record types we have.
DNS record types are records that provide important information about a host name or domain.
This record includes the current IP address for a domain.
Also DNS records are stored in a test files, rather zone files.
On the authoritative DNS server, the content of a DNS record file is a string with special commands that the DNS server has on a stand.
So for the different records, for example, we have the error code.
The error code is most commonly used to map a fully qualified domain name,
other fully qualified domain name to an IP address, and act as it translates to by
name to IP address.
So what is the error code used for?
The main use of the error code is for IP address to look up.
So using an error code, for example, a web browser is able to load a website using the domain name.
As a result, we can assess websites on the internet without knowing the IP address.
Then we have what we call the QUAD error, the AA record, seeing that the error code must one IP fashion cease address.
So a smart phone, for example, they prefer to use the IP version cease if it is available.
So what do you use the AA record?
For the usage of the error code for DNS solution has a great potential because they use the IP version cease with an improvement of our IP version.
For now, we know how the scene name record, which is actually a fully called the
kernel, the kernel, the kernel name, which is the code for now, the kernel name.
So an alias is an alias that points to another domain of sub domain, but never an IP address.
So the alias recorded my PIN is the FQDN to multiple hosts to a single location.
So what do you use the same name, the scene name records for?
A first example, the use of scene name record is running multiple sub domains for different purpose of the same server.
For example, we have also the S2A record, which you've seen in some of the video
Academy DNS, as a start of authority, which stores information about domains and it's used to direct how it DNS zone propagated to secondary name server.
Also, how the DNS record, which of course is spent fine with name servers are targeted for domain or sub domain.
And also, we have the MS record, which is the mail S10 server, which uses the mail server to map where to deliver emails for domain.
And also, we also have the tst data test record, which allows them straight to add limited human and machine readable note and can be used for teams such as email validation site and ownership verification.
Also, how the SRV record, which allows services such an instant messaging of voice to be directed to separate hosts and ports location.
So, we also have all called the PTR record, which is called the point I record.
So it's a reverse of the A and A, A record with maps IP address to domain name.
And then lastly, we have the SPF record as a center policy framework, which helps prevent emails moving and limits spammas.